English is full of colourful phrases to describe shyness.
英语中有很多生动的短语来描述害羞。
Someone timid might be called a shrinking violet or a wallflower, while for especially nervous types we have the curious expression: they wouldn't say boo to a goose.
胆小的人可能会被称为害羞的人或壁花，而对于特别紧张的人，我们有一个有趣的表达：他们连对一只鹅说声“嘘”都不敢。
None of these are traditionally seen as positive descriptions, even if you like geese.
传统上，这些都不被视为正面的描述，即使你喜欢鹅。
In a culture of go-getting high achievers, shy people don't come first.
在一个崇尚积极进取成功人士的文化中，害羞的人不重要。
Or that's what the self-help industry would have you believe.
或者说，这就是自助行业想让你相信的。
Bookshops are filled with weighty tomes that promise to help beat social fears and find success in life, love and business.
书店里摆满了厚重的书籍，这些书承诺能帮助人们战胜社交恐惧，并在生活、爱情和事业中取得成功。
Which is why one book, Shrinking Violets: A Field Guide to Shyness, bucks the trend.
这就是为什么有一本书，《害羞的人：害羞者指南》，逆势而行。
It made a splash across English-language media recently for its new take on bashfulness.
最近，它因其对羞怯的新看法而在英语媒体上引起轰动。
Author Joe Moran says that despite struggling with shyness and craving solitude all his life, being timid can also be "a gift".
作者乔·莫兰说，尽管他一生都在与害羞作斗争，并且一直渴望独处，但胆小也可以是“一份礼物”。
Freed from the persistent urge to participate and compete in social situations, people are liberated to look at the world in new ways, and gain fresh insights.
摆脱了在社交场合中参与和竞争的持续冲动，人们被解放出来，以新的方式看待世界，并获得新的见解。
Indeed, many of the world's great thinkers and artists are introverts.
确实，世界上许多伟大的思想家和艺术家都是内向的人。
Scientists Charles Darwin and Albert Einstein preferred their own company; actress Keira Knightley often finds herself tongue-tied at parties; and Harry Potter author JK Rowling claims she used to be too nervous to even borrow a pen - a reticence she says forced her to delve deep into the world of her imagination.
科学家查尔斯·达尔文和阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦更喜欢独处；女演员凯拉·奈特莉在聚会上常常发现自己张口结舌；《哈利·波特》的作者J.K.罗琳声称她曾经紧张到甚至不敢借一支笔——她说这种沉默寡言迫使她深入探索自己的想象世界。
Moran told BBC Future: "I think shyness probably does turn you into an amateur anthropologist, really - you are more likely to be an observer."
莫兰告诉英国广播公司《未来》栏目：“我认为害羞可能真的会让你成为一名业余的人类学家，你更有可能成为一名观察者。”
So, while extroverts make all the noise, they don't necessarily have the best ideas.
所以，虽然外向的人总是吵吵闹闹，但他们不一定有最好的想法。
If you're shy, you've probably known this for a long time.
如果你很害羞，你可能早就知道这一点了。
You just don't shout about it.
你只是不会大肆宣扬而已。